- 让我们研究如何针对问答场景
- Let's study how to preprocess a dataset
预处理数据集。
for question answering.
问答场景是在一些上下文环境下
Question answering is a task
针对某个问题寻找其答案的应用场景。
of finding answers to a question in some context.
例如，我们将使用 SQuAD 数据集
For example, we'll use the SQuAD dataset
在其中我们删除了我们不会使用的列
in which we remove columns we won't use
并针对标签提取
and just extract the information we will need
我们需要的信息，
for the labels,
即上下文中答案的开始和结束。
the start and the end of the answer in the context.
如果你有自己的问答数据集，
If you have your own dataset for question answering,
只要确保你清理数据以达到同一效果，
just make sure you clean your data to get to the same point,
其中一列包含问题，
with one column containing the questions,
一列包含上下文，
one column containing the context,
一列为上下文中的答案的
one column for the index of the start and end character
起始和终止字符的索引。
of the answer in the context.
请注意，答案必须是上下文的一部分。
Note that the answer must be part of the context.
如果你想进行生成式问答，
If you want to perform generative question answering,
查看下面链接的视频序列之一。
look at one of the sequence to sequence videos linked below.
现在，如果我们看一下
Now, if we have a look at the tokens
我们将输入给我们的模型的词元，
we will feed our model,
我们会看到答案就在上下文中的某个地方。
we'll see the answer lies somewhere inside the context.
对于很长的上下文，该答案可能
For very long context, that answer may get truncated
会被分词器截断。
by the tokenizer.
在这种情况下，我们的模型将没有任何合适的标签，
In this case, we won't have any proper labels for our model,
所以我们应该
so we should keep the truncated part
保留截断的部分作为一个单独的功能而不是丢弃它。
as a separate feature instead of discarding it.
我们唯一需要小心的是
The only thing we need to be careful with
是允许单独的块之间有一些重叠
is to allow some overlap between separate chunks
这样答案就不会被截断
so that the answer is not truncated
使得包含答案的特征
and that the feature containing the answer
获得足够的上下文来预测它。
gets sufficient context to be able to predict it.
这是分词器如何完成的。
Here is how it can be done by the tokenizer.
我们将问题、上下文传递给它，
We pass it the question, context, set a truncation
仅针对上下文设置截断，并且填充到最大长度。
for the context only, and the padding to the maximum length.
stride 参数是我们针对重叠的词元
The stride argument is where we set the number
设置数字的地方，
of overlapping tokens,
并且return_overflowing_tokens 等于 true
and the return overflowing tokens equals true
意味着我们不想丢弃截断的部分。
means we don't want to discard the truncated part.
最后，我们还返回 return_offsets_mapping
Lastly, we also return the offset mappings
从而能够找到和答案的起始与结束相关的
to be able to find the tokens corresponding
相应的词元。
to the answer start and end.
我们想要保留这些词元，因为它们将成为标签
We want those tokens because they will be the labels
我们将其传递给我们的模型。
we pass through our model.
在独热编码版本中，这是它们的样子。
In a one-hot encoded version, here is what they look like.
如果我们的上下文不包含答案，
If the context we have does not contain the answer,
我们将这两个标签设置为 CLS 词元的索引。
we set the two labels to the index of the CLS token.
如果上下文仅部分包含答案，
We also do this if the context
我们也会这样做。
only partially contains the answer.
在代码方面，这是我们如何做到的。
In terms of code, here is how we can do it.
使用输入的序列 ID，
Using the sequence IDs of an input,
我们可以确定上下文的开始和结束。
we can determine the beginning and the end of the context.
然后，我们就知道是否需要
Then, we know if we have to return to the CLS position
根据两个标签返回 CLS 位置
for the two labels or we determine the position
或者我们确定答案的第一个和最后一个词元的位置。
of the first and last tokens of the answer.
我们可以在前面的示例中检查它是否正常发挥作用。
We can check it works properly on our previous example.
把它们放在一起看起来就像这个大函数，
Putting it all together looks like this big function,
我们可以使用 map 方法将其应用于我们的数据集。
which we can apply to our datasets with the map method.
由于我们在词元化过程中应用了填充操作，
Since we applied padding during the tokenization,
然后我们可以直接作为训练器使用
we can then use this directly as the trainer
或者应用 to_tf_dataset 方法来使用 Keras.fit。
or apply the to_tf_dataset method to use Keras.fit.